Pius Ashogbon Godwin

Tel: 09052794388 Address: Oworoshoki Lagos, Nigeria Email: Pius1ash@gmail.com
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/piusash

Github: https://github.com/PiusAsh

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | WORDPRESS DEVELOPER

Ambitious Software Developer & WordPress Developer versed in following established procedures and working under little or no supervision. Offering technical expertise in programming analysis, application analysis, and design.

Excellent team player with in-depth knowledge of development tools and languages.

SKILLS

- Angular
- JavaScript & TypeScript
- C#
- ASP.NET
- WordPress
- Microsoft SQL
- Hosting / Deployment / cPanel

- Seo Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Project Management (Jira, Trello, GitHub)
- Version Control System (GitHub, and Bitbucket)
- Graphic Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Information Engineering Technologies Limited, Internship

Software Developer | March 2022 - Present

- Collaborate productively with the product team to understand requirements and business specifications around portfolio management, analytics, and risk.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Developed software for desktop and mobile operating systems.
- Coordinated with project management on database development timelines.
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve user experience.
- Solved complex problems using the latest web technologies.
- Develop and present findings and solutions to audiences including senior executives and stakeholders.

Digitalweb Applications Development Limited

WordPress Developer | May, 2022 - November 2022

Build WordPress sites using Elementor page builder and WpBakery

- Prepare website proposals to present to clients
- Write code using HTML and CSS.
- Design new features for existing websites
- Customize themes to meet clients' requirements.
- Manage a user guide to help clients understand site features and management of the website to increase visitor satisfaction.
- Integrating payment gateway
- Setting up search engine optimization

Innkeeper

Frontend Developer Intern | November 2021 - February 2022

Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software

- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery.
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.
- Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team.
- Identifying innovative ideas and proof of concepts according to project requirements
- Providing guidance and troubleshooting support to clients
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like Trello, or GitHub

Ashconcept Digital Solutions

WordPress Developer | June 2018 - February 2021

- Build WordPress sites using Elementor page builder
- Prepare website proposals to present to clients
- Write code using HTML and CSS.
- Design new features for existing websites
- Customize themes to meet clients' requirements.
- Manage a user guide to help clients understand site features and management of the website to increase visitor satisfaction.
- Integrating payment gateway
- Setting up search engine optimization

EDUCATION & TRAINING

➤ Ordinary National Diploma (OND), Business Administration | 2018 - 2021 Yaba College of Technology

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

- > Frontend Web Development, Innkeeper | February 2022
- > Digital Marketing, Indian Institute of Digital Education (IIDE) | June 2021
- ➤ WordPress Development, Webbiit Technologies | 2020
 - ➤ WordPress Development, Udemy | 2021
 - ➤ Microsoft SQL Masterclass, Udemy | 2022
- Project Management, Simplilearn | 2022